RESUME

Arun kumar. V

No: 15, Gandhima nagar,

Coimbatore. Tamil Nadu – 641006

Mobile: +91-9578477995

Email ID: arunkumargiri07@gmail.com

Professional Summary

US based Medical Billing professional with 7+ year's experience on handling AR Revenue Generation and Billing. Currently working as a Quality Group coordinator for two locations with the team size of 16 auditors . Handling RCM process for the client and regulating the Cash Flow in accordance with all the Compliance and Regulation.

Career Objective

To pursue my career in an invigorating environment and to get a challenging position in where I can grow professionally and become a valuable asset.

Career Highlights

I have received the below recognition for my continuous exceptional performance.

- Awarded with best performer of the month and best Group coordinator of the quarter.
- Supported in Business research development team for appeal automation process.
- Successfully transitioned an 4 month old RCM project to another location after stabilizing it

•

 Along with sound experience in AR vertical, additionally having knowledge in Complete RCM processes as follows, End to end Demo / change entry, Patient billing, Appeals, Provider enrollment & Refunds

Work Experience:

1. Vee technologies Pvt Ltd

Joined on April 2015 – May 2016

Job Title AR Specialist

2. Wave online Pvt Ltd

Joined on June 2016 – December 2016 Job Title Senior process executive.

3. LogixHealth Solutions Pvt Ltd

Joined on December 2016 – April 2021

Job Title * Senior provider reimbursement specialist – ATB

process

* Senior Quality analyst - Provider Reimbursement

department.

5. **Quintessence business solutions**

Joined on May 2021 – Current

Job Title Group coordinator Quality (Billing & AR) - Handling Team

size of 16 Quality Analysts Coordinating in two

locations.

Present roles & Responsibilities as Group coordinator

Client Management:

- First level SPOC with clients to make sure cascading new updates to team / responding to their clarifications & escalations as per TAT.
- Ensure reconciliation status shared to client on daily basis.
- Quality and training SPOC for new client transitions.
- Publishing monthly / weekly reports to clients and Management.
- Make sure planning and completing random / needy base inventory requests from client as per their expectations on TAT.
- Maintaining healthy and high professional communication with client to maintain the business and grasp new business to the company.

Team Management:

- Monitor, identify and resolve performance/behavior/attendance issues using prescribed performance management techniques.
- Conducting daily / weekly / monthly connect with team to communicate all process and client updates and documenting through MOM
- Ensure training needs of subordinates are met
- Open for Team members to approach me for all their job related needs and create a harmonious work environment
- Bridging Employee performance appreciations / issues with Hierarchy / Reporting managers on a timely manner
- Responsible for day-to-day functional supervision of work group, including work assignment and attendance monitoring; providing input into selecting, training, developing, and completing performance appraisal of work group(s) in accordance with the organization's policies and applicable compliance requirements.
- Conduct performance appraisals annually along with Manager.

Educational Qualification:

Year of	Degree/Course	Board of Study	Institute & Place
Passing			

2015	B.Tech- IT	Anna University	Karpagam institute of Technology, coimbatore.
2011	HSC	Matriculation	U.R.C matriculation Higher Secondary School, Erode.
2009	10th	Matriculation	U.R.C matriculation Higher Secondary School , Erode.

Personal Profile

Father's Name : M. Vellingiri

Gender : Male

Marital status : No

Nationality : Indian

Permanent Address : 4/7, 3rd cross street jeeva nagar,

Erode road, perundurai- 6380052

Languages proficiency : Tamil & English (Read / write / Speak)

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above-furnished details are true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Thank You,

Date : (Arun Kumar.V)